Drake Hopkins Lakeland, FL

drakehopkins@outlook.com 870.273.2315

drakeafk.io | GitHub | LinkedIn

Summary

Web Developer & IT Professional with 4+ years of industry experience. Has built numerous websites and web applications and has held roles performing a variety of IT-related tasks. Specializes in HTML, CSS, and JavaScript, while continually exploring and mastering different technologies. Experience also extends to working with Bootstrap, Svelte & SvelteKit, as well as other languages/environments including NodeJS, Python, and Rust.

Skills	
Operating Systems	Windows (8/10/11), Linux (Ubuntu, Arch, Kali), macOS, iOS, iPadOS, Android
Hardware Proficiencies	Desktops, Laptops, Printers & Scanners, Routers, Modems & Switches, Mobile Devices
Software & Collaboration Tools	Microsoft Office, Google Workspace, Active Directory, PowerShell/Terminal, SSH, VPN, Remote Desktop, Virtualization, Google Cloud Platform
Web Development Skills	HTML, CSS, JavaScript, NodeJS, Svelte & SvelteKit, Astro, TailwindCSS, Bootstrap, Python, Rust, Responsive Design
Design & Editing Tools	Adobe Creative Cloud/Suite, Figma (WireFraming)

Education

Arkansas State University

08/2014 - 05/2019

Bachelor of Arts in Political Science

- Completed many different courses outside of degree requirements in various academic disciplines:
 - Mathematics; Computer Science; Biology; Chemistry; Psychology.

Certifications

- Google IT Support; Google IT Automation with Python; Systems Administration and IT Infrastructure Services
- JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures; Responsive Web Design; Complete WebDev Bootcamp.
- 120-Hour TESOL/TEFL (Teaching English as a Foreign Language).

Experience

Web Developer – DAFK (Freelance)

08/2019 - Present

- Design and develop websites for individuals and small businesses
- Utilize HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and a variety frameworks/libraries/environments including NodeJS, Svelte & SvelteKit, Astro, React, TailwindCSS, and Bootstrap (Plus brief backend work with Python and Rust)
- Manage multiple projects simultaneously

IT Consultant – City Government

11/2022 - 06/2023

- Install and configure devices, hardware, and applications
- Troubleshoot hardware, software, and network problems
- Implement new IT systems and update infrastructure

Junior Frontend Developer – Emergency Services

06/2019 - 09/2022

- Support in designing and maintaining the frontend of web pages and applications
- Collaborate with backend developers to ensure seamless integration of frontend and backend components
- Optimize web pages and applications for maximum speed, scalability, and security
- Stay up to date with emerging trends and technologies in frontend development

IT Support (Intern) – Farmers Elevator

04/2016 - 03/2019

- Setup and maintain Windows and Linux systems
- Form data backup and disaster recovery plans
- Network troubleshooting

MISC Experience

English Language Tutor – Freelance

07/2022 - 05/2023

- Tutor students learning English as a second language
- Design and implement plans and procedures for students to meet their English language goals
- Work with students internationally at varying ages and educational levels